<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aditya Sharma</title>
    <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aditya Sharma</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 19:39:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://aditya-dev.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#33: Random Blabber</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p764/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 19:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p764/</guid>
      <description>A certain someone inspired me to write this down, after so long a time. She doesn&amp;#8217;t know about this, so hopefully she&amp;#8217;ll not be reading it anytime soon. For lack of something good, I&amp;#8217;ll just update y&amp;#8217;all on my life and university (something that&amp;#8217;s a headline for this blog)
I got into my last year of Engineering this semester. Contrary to my thoughts, I ended up passing all my courses from last semester.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#32: Google Summer of Code : Pencils Down</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p723/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 17:37:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p723/</guid>
      <description>Wow ! What a summer !
Roughly 12 weeks have passed since I started working on KDE Now (well formally). Results came out some couple of hours ago and I passed the full term evaluation. In this post, I&amp;#8217;m going to talk about what I&amp;#8217;m planning for the future of KDE Now. How the past weeks have been and some other stuff.
&amp;nbsp;
To start with, the summer was awesome. I got to learn so much and that certainly made me a better programmer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#31: GSoC with KDE Now – 9</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p674/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2016 18:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p674/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! I’m making KDE Now, an application for the Plasma Desktop. It would help the user see important stuff from his email, on a plasmoid. It’s similar to what Google Now does on Android. To know more, click here.
&amp;nbsp;
Roughly three weeks have passed since I last blogged about my project. School started and it was tough finding time for everything let alone blogging. This year&amp;#8217;s Summer of Code is reaching it&amp;#8217;s end and I have much to talk about this time around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#30: GSoC with KDE Now – 8</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p644/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 18:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p644/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! I’m making KDE Now, an application for the Plasma Desktop. It would help the user see important stuff from his email, on a plasmoid. It’s similar to what Google Now does on Android. To know more, click here.
&amp;nbsp;
Time sure passes fast when you are enjoying something. And so, another week has passed and I&amp;#8217;m back with another status update. Things look very very good from here on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#29: GSoC with KDE Now – 7</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p606/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2016 17:39:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p606/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! I’m making KDE Now, an application for the Plasma Desktop. It would help the user see important stuff from his email, on a plasmoid. It’s similar to what Google Now does on Android. To know more, click here
&amp;nbsp;
Another week has passed. And I&amp;#8217;m back with more updates of what I&amp;#8217;ve done over last week. I worked on the plasmoid side of things this time. Andres(Andy) Betts at the KDE-VDG was very generous and had given me some nice mockups for Event and Hotel cards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#28: GSoC with KDE Now – 6</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p563/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 08:25:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p563/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! I’m making KDE Now, an application for the Plasma Desktop. It would help the user see important stuff from his email, on a plasmoid. It’s similar to what Google Now does on Android. To know more, click here
&amp;nbsp;
Another week has passed since I last posted about my progress. This week I did more work primarily on the plasmoid side of things.
I added receivers for the data, that was being thrown over D-Bus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#27: GSoC with KDE Now – 5</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p539/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 08:46:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p539/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! I&amp;#8217;m making KDE Now, an application for the Plasma Desktop. It would help the user see important stuff from his email, on a plasmoid. It&amp;#8217;s similar to what Google Now does on Android. To know more, click here
&amp;nbsp;
I know, I know. I haven&amp;#8217;t blogged for a while. But the past couple of weeks have been busy. Not just in terms of my project, but also my personal life, with a lot of things happening lately that demand my attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#26: GSoC with KDE Now – 4</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p465/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 14:34:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p465/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! I&amp;#8217;m making KDE Now, an application for the Plasma Desktop. It would help the user see important stuff from his email, on a plasmoid. It&amp;#8217;s similar to what Google Now does on Android. To know more, click here
&amp;nbsp;
In the past week, I worked on the code reviews I got. Hence, I changed the classes&amp;#8217; design all over. The way it works now, is that there is a central dispatcher, the daemon, that handles all the jobs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#25: Summers !</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p432/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 07:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p432/</guid>
      <description>I had my last exam on the 27th of May. And with that, I bid adieu to my sophomore year. Now when I look back, things seem to have flown past. Just the other day, I was excited about starting another year at college, and here I am writing about it&amp;#8217;s end. Life sure moves fast, mate.
Last year (or academic session) was a mix bag. We had some good courses, and some not so good ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#24: GSoC with KDE Now – 3</title>
      <link>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p359/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2016 19:43:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aditya-dev.xyz/p359/</guid>
      <description>Hey ! I&amp;#8217;m making KDE Now, an application for the Plasma Desktop. It would help the user see important stuff from his email, on a plasmoid. It&amp;#8217;s similar to what Google Now does on Android. To know more, click here
&amp;nbsp;
It&amp;#8217;s been some time since the coding period started for this year&amp;#8217;s Summer of Code. I had exams till 27th of May, so I started from 28th. My mentor knew about it already, so things went buttery smooth.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>